A Guide to the Press Office Records of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1993-1998
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Photographs, 1993-1998., Extent: 5.4 cubic feet. (Box 26-37)
  - 1997.
    - Governor's Advisory Board on Child Abuse and Neglect Appreciation Awards Ceremony (First Lady), 1997 November 13. (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Governor's Advisory Council on Revenue Estimates, 1997 November 14. (Box 37, Folder 37-38)
    - Social Service Conference on Welfare Reform, 1997 November 17. (Box 37, Folder 39-40)
    - Industrial Galvanizers Opening and Dedication in Petersburg, 1997 November 18. (Box 37, Folder 41-42)
    - Medals of Life Ceremony (Governor and Mrs. Allen Present Medals to Family Members to Honor Virginia Organ Donors), 1997 November 19. (Box 37, Folder 43-44)
    - Volunteerism Awards (Governor and Mrs. Allen Recognize Outstanding Volunteers throughout the Commonwealth), 1997 November 25. (Box 37, Folder 45-46)
    - Volunteerism Awards (Jimmy and Donna Dean Introduce "Virginia," 1997 November 25. (Box 37, Folder 47)
    - Former Redskins and Spouses for Dinner at the Executive Mansion, 1997 November 25. (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - Indian Tax Ceremony, 1997 November 26. (Box 37, Folder 49-50)
    - Southwest Virginia Higher Education Center Opening Ceremony, 1997 December 1. (Box 37, Folder 51-54)
    - Iridium, LLC Opening Ceremony, 1997 December 2. (Box 37, Folder 55-56)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 1997 December 2. (Box 37, Folder 57)
    - Swearing-in of Virginia Senator Randy Forbes, 1997 December 6. (Box 37, Folder 58)
    - Budget Announcement (Roanoke), 1997 December 12. (Box 37, Folder 59)
    - Budget Announcement (Old Dominion University), 1997 December 10. (Box 37, Folder 60-61)
    - Route 288 Ribbon Cutting (Goochland County), 1997 December 8. (Box 37, Folder 62-63)
    - Press Conference: Motorola Announces Expansion of Planned Facility in Virginia, 1997 December 3. (Box 37, Folder 64-66)
    - State Christmas Tree Lighting (First Family with Santa Claus), 1997 December 3. (Box 37, Folder 67-68)
    - State Christmas Tree Lighting (First Family Brings Christmas Greetings to those Assembled), 1997 December 3. (Box 37, Folder 69-70)
    - State Christmas Tree Lighting (Tyler and Forrest Light the Tree), 1997 December 3. (Box 37, Folder 71)
    - State Christmas Tree Lighting (Governor and Mrs. Allen Greet Visitors to the Annual Christmas Open House at the Executive Mansion), 1997 December 3. (Box 37, Folder 72-73)
    - Press Conference: James Karlick Returns NFL Ring Belonging to Governor Allen's Father (Ring Found at Albany, NY Airport), 1997 December 4. (Box 37, Folder 74)
    - Fort Pickett Community Appreciation Day (Celebrating the Turning over of the Fort to the Virginia National Guard), 1997 December 4. (Box 37, Folder 75-76)
    - Fort Pickett Community Appreciation Day (Celebrating the Turning over of the Fort to the Virginia National Guard--Team Photograph Shows Those Instrumental to the Acquisition), 1997 December 4. (Box 37, Folder 77)
    - GE Capitol Finance Assurance Ribbon Cutting, 1997 December 5. (Box 37, Folder 78-79)
    - Education Awards, 1997 December 8. (Box 37, Folder 80-81)
    - Press Conference: Announcement of Richmond Centre Expansion, 1997 December 9. (Box 37, Folder 82-83)
    - Budget Announcement (Poplar Forest), 1997 December 10. (Box 37, Folder 84-87)
    - Budget Annoucement (Barter Theatre), 1997 December 11. (Box 37, Folder 88-89)
    - Governor Allen Competes in NFL Picks with Local Sportscasters and "Miss Jenkins," a Potbellied Pig on XL102--The Governor had the Most Successful Season, 1997 December 12. (Box 37, Folder 90)
    - Budget Announcement (Jamestown), 1997 December 12. (Box 37, Folder 91-93)
    - Budget Announcement (Virginia Mariners Museum), 1997 December 13. (Box 37, Folder 94-96)
    - Budget Announcement with First Family (Science Museum of Virginia), 1997 December 14. (Box 37, Folder 97-98)
    - Budget Annoucement (Virginia Natural History Museum), 1997 December 15. (Box 37, Folder 99-101)
    - Announcement of Recycling Center (Dinwiddie County), 1997 December 15. (Box 37, Folder 102-104)
    - Budget Announcement (Beaumont Correctional Facility), 1997 December 16. (Box 37, Folder 105-109)
    - Bridgewater College Announcement of Proposed Increase in Tuition Assistance Grant to Aid Virginia Students Attending Private Colleges, 1997 December 16. (Box 37, Folder 110-112)
    - Agency Head Reception (Governor Receives Distinguished Service Medal from the Virginia National Guard), 1997 December 16. (Box 37, Folder 113-114)
    - Budget Announcement Regarding Higher Education at the University of Virginia, 1997 December 17. (Box 37, Folder 115-116)
    - Budget Announcement (Lynchburg), 1997 December 17. (Box 37, Folder 117-118)
    - Budget Annoucement (Math and Science Center in Richmond), 1997 December 18. (Box 37, Folder 119-120)
    - Budget Presentation, 1997 December 19. (Box 37, Folder 121-124)
    - Press Conference: Regulatory Reform, 1997 December 22. (Box 37, Folder 125)
    - Governor Allen with Current and Former Staff Members of the Policy Office, 1997 December 22. (Box 37, Folder 126)
    - American Lung Association and its 1997 Christmas Seal, 1997 December 22. (Box 37, Folder 127)
    - Navy League Conducts Yearly Inspection of the Bell from the Decommissioned U.S.S. Virginia Located in the State Capitol, 1997 December 22. (Box 37, Folder 128)
    - First Family with Members of the Executive Protection Unit of the Virginia State Police, 1997 December 23. (Box 37, Folder 129)
    - Governor Allen is Honored by the Richmond Renegades Hockey Team, 1997 December 27. (Box 37, Folder 130-131)
    - Announcement of Ferguson Enterprises' Plans to Build a New Facility in Front Royal, 1997 December 29. (Box 37, Folder 132-133)
    - Reynolds Metals Announces Expansion of its Lebanon Reynolds Wheel Facility, 1997 December 30. (Box 37, Folder 134-137)
    - Governor Delivers on Promise to Promote Southwest Virginia, 1997 December 30. (Box 37, Folder 138)
  - 1998.
    - Governor's Cabinet, 1998 January 6. (Box 37, Folder 139)
    - Governor Allen and Tennessee Governor Don Sundquist to Announce Tennessee/Virginia Regional Task Force Formed to Promote Southwest Virginia and Northeast Tennessee, 1998 January 7. (Box 37, Folder 140)
    - Board of Education, 1998 January 8. (Box 37, Folder 141-142)
    - Virginia History Initiative at Virginia Historical Society / Press Conference for New Facility for the Department of Historic Resources, 1998 January 8. (Box 37, Folder 143-144)
    - Dedication of the Susan Allen Mammography Suite at the Mammography Services for Central Virginia, 1998 January 8. (Box 37, Folder 145-148)
    - Governor's Work Force Taskforce, 1998 January 9. (Box 37, Folder 149-150)
    - Governor's Portrait Unveiling (Portrait by Claiborne Gregory, Jr.), 1998 January 9. (Box 37, Folder 151-152)
    - Governor's Official Portrait in State Capitol, 1998 January 9. (Box 37, Folder 153)
    - Governor Addresses the Attorney General's Office, 1998 January 9. (Box 37, Folder 154)
    - Hanging of the Governor's Official Portrait, 1998 January 12. (Box 37, Folder 155-157)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address, 1998 January 14. (Box 37, Folder 158-159)
    - Inauguration of Governor Jim Gilmore (Governor Allen Handing over Keys to the Executive Mansion), 1998 January 17. (Box 37, Folder 160)
    - Inauguration of Governor Jim Gilmore (Allen and Gilmore Families), 1998 January 17. (Box 37, Folder 161)
    - End of Allen Administration (Allen Family Leaving the Executive Mansion), 1998 January 17. (Box 37, Folder 162-164)
    - Miscellaneous Contact Sheets and Negatives, undated. (Box 37, Folder 165)
- Series III. Press Releases, 1993-1998., Extent: 2.35 cubic feet. (Box 38-40)
  (Accession 35746). Contains press releases issued by the Press Office of Governor George Allen. Also included are releases issued by Governor-elect Allen's Transition Office before his inauguration. The releases announce appointments, business expansions, swearings-in, grant funding, media advisories for public appearances, trade missions, and select activities of First Lady Susan Allen. In limited cases, remarks and speech transcripts are also included with the press releases.
  - 1993 November-December. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - 1994 January. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - 1994 February. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - 1994 March. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - 1994 April. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - 1994 May. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - 1994 June. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - 1994 July. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - 1994 August. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - 1994 September 1-13. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - 1994 September 15-30. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - 1994 October. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - 1994 November. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - 1994 December. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - 1995 January 3-19. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - 1995 January 20-31. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - 1995 February. (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - 1995 March 1-20. (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - 1995 March 21-31. (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - 1995 April 3-4. (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - 1995 April 5-14. (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - 1995 April 18-28. (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - 1995 May. (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - 1995 June. (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - 1995 July 1-14. (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - 1995 July 17-31. (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - 1995 August 1-14. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - 1995 August 15-31. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - 1995 September. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - 1995 October. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - 1995 November. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - 1995 December. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - 1996 January 1-15. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - 1996 January 16-31. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - 1996 February. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - 1996 March. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - 1996 April 1-12. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - 1996 April 15-30. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - 1996 May. (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - 1996 June 4-19. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - 1996 June 20-29. (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - 1996 July 1-8. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - 1996 July 9-12. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - 1996 July 16-30. (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - 1996 August. (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - 1996 September. (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - 1996 October. (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - 1996 November 1-14. (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - 1996 November 18-29. (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - 1996 December 2-12. (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - 1996 December 16-31. (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - 1997 January. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - 1997 February 1-19. (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - 1997 February 20-27. (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - 1997 March 5-13. (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - 1997 March 14-18. (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - 1997 March 19-27. (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - 1997 April 1-17. (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - 1997 April 18-30. (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - 1997 May 1-16. (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - 1997 May 19-30. (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - 1997 June 2-9. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - 1997 June 10-16. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - 1997 June 17-30. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - 1997 July 1-14. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - 1997 July 15-31. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - 1997 August. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - 1997 September 2-12. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - 1997 September 15-19. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - 1997 September 22-30. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - 1997 October. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - 1997 November. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - 1997 December 1-15. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - 1997 December 16-31. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - 1998 January. (Box 40, Folder 14)
- Series IV. Proclamations and Certificates of Recognition, 1994-1998., Extent: 3.3 cubic feet. (Box 40-43.)
  (Accession 35716). Contains copies of proclamations and certificates of recogition issued and signed by Governor George Allen. These documents recognize citizens, programs, anniversaries, events, and are used designate days, weeks, and months for special observance in the Commonwealth. Some files also include background documentation including correspondence, clippings, reference material, and press releases.
  The proclamations and certificates of recognition are filed together and arranged chronologically by month. Undated documents can be found in the first folder for each year.
  - 1994. (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - 1994 January. (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - 1994 February. (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - 1994 March. (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - 1994 April. (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - 1994 May. (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - 1994 June. (Box 40, Folder 36)
  - 1994 July. (Box 40, Folder 37)
  - 1994 August. (Box 40, Folder 38)
  - 1994 September. (Box 40, Folder 39)
  - 1994 October. (Box 40, Folder 40)
  - 1994 November. (Box 40, Folder 41)
  - 1994 December. (Box 40, Folder 42)
  - 1995. (Box 40, Folder 43)
  - 1994 January. (Box 40, Folder 44)
  - 1994 February. (Box 40, Folder 45)
  - 1995 February. (Box 40, Folder 46)
  - 1995 March. (Box 40, Folder 47)
  - 1995 March. (Box 40, Folder 48)
  - 1995 April. (Box 40, Folder 49)
  - 1995 April. (Box 40, Folder 50)
  - 1995 April. (Box 40, Folder 51)
  - 1995 April. (Box 40, Folder 52)
  - 1995 May. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - 1995 May. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - 1995 May. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - 1995 June. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - 1995 June. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - 1995 July. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - 1995 August. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - 1995 September. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - 1995 September. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - 1995 October. (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - 1995 October. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - 1995 October. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - 1995 November. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - 1995 December. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - 1996. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - 1996 January. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - 1996 February. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - 1996 March. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - 1996 April. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - 1996 April. (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - 1996 April. (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - 1996 May. (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - 1996 May. (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - 1996 June. (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - 1996 July. (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - 1996 July. (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - 1996 August. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 1996 September. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1996 September. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 1996 September. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 1996 October. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 1996 October. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - 1996 October. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - 1996 October. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - 1996 October. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - 1996 November. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - 1996 November. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - 1996 December. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - 1997. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - 1997 January. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - 1997 January. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - 1997 February. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - 1997 February. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - 1997 March. (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - 1997 March. (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - 1997 March. (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - 1997 April. (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - 1997 April. (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - 1997 April. (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - 1997 April. (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - 1997 May. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - 1997 May. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - 1997 May. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - 1997 May. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 1997 May. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - 1997 June. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - 1997 June. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - 1997 June. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - 1997 July. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - 1997 August. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - 1997 September. (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - 1997 September. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - 1997 September. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - 1997 October. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - 1997 October. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - 1997 October. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - 1997 October. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - 1997 November. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - 1997 November. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - 1997 November. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - 1997 December. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - 1998 January. (Box 43, Folder 22)
- Series V. Publications, 1994-1997; undated., Extent: .15 cu. ft. (Box 40.)
  (Accession 35746). Contains publications collected by the Press Office that feature articles written by or about Governor George Allen. Also included are transcripts of his State of the Commonwealth addresses for 1996 and 1997, and undated brochures about the Executive Mansion and the Capitol's Third Floor Portrait Gallery.
  - Trooper, 1994 Spring. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - UVA Lawyer, 1994 Summer. (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - The Republican Woman, 1994 Summer/Fall. (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Review, 1994 September/October. (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Librarian, 1994 Fall. (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Police Journal, 1994 Winter. (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - The American Enterprise, 1995 March/April. (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Journal of Law and Public Policy, 1995 Spring. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Policy Review, 1995 Spring. (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 1996. (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 1997. (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Richmond, 1997 August. (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - The Executive Mansion, undated. (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - The Governors of Virginia: A Guide to the Capitol's Third Floor Portrait Gallery, undated. (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Progress, undated. (Box 40, Folder 29)
- Series VI. Speeches, 1994-1998., Extent: .4 cubic feet. (Box 44.)
  (Accession 35863). Contains prepared remarks for speeches made by Governor George Allen. The speeches include those delivered at college graduations, conferences and forums, ribbon-cuttings, public announcements, and to the General Assembly. Also included are the texts for Governor Allen's State of the Commonwealth addresses.
  The speeches are arranged chronologically by the month in which they were delivered.
  - 1994 January-March. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - 1994 April-May. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 1994 June-July. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - 1994 August-October. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 1994 November-December. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - 1995 January-February. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - 1995 March-April. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - 1995 May-June. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - 1995 July-August. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - 1995 September-October. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - 1995 November-December. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - 1996 January-March. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - 1996 April-May. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - 1996 June-July. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - 1996 August-October. (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - 1996 November-December. (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - 1997 January-February. (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - 1997 March-April. (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - 1997 May-July. (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - 1997 August-October. (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - 1997 November-1998 January. (Box 44, Folder 21)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous Press Office Files, 1994-1997., Extent: .15 cubic feet. (Box 44.)
  (Accessions 35430 and 35863). Contains three files related to the activities of the Press Office during the Allen administration. The first folder contains inaugural briefing materials distributed to the media. The material includes time schedules and fact sheets for the inaugural events and is part of accession 35430. The second folder contains visitor registration logs that contain names, addresses, and comments left by visitors to the Governor's Office for the years 1996-1997. The final folder contains print-outs of Governor Allen's Web site as it was in November 1997. The print-outs include an organizational chart, biographical information, and descriptions of state agencies and cabinet secretaries. The visitor logs and Web site files are part of accession 35863.
  The miscellaneous files are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Inaugural Briefing Material, 1994. (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Visitor Registration Logs, 1996-1997. (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Web Site, 1997. (Box 44, Folder 24)